Azizun Begum

CRM Admin | Analyst | Consultant

azizunbegum@gmail.com +971509064185 https://www.linkedin.com/in/azizun29/

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am into Customer Relationship Management (Salesforce, Zoho) with 5 years of experience holding Salesforce Certification.

Insightful skill sets who are organized with great attention to detail. Able to function as result oriented resource in different platforms across multiple projects.

Strong analytical and problem solving skills with client management. Excellent teamwork.

SKILLS

Development Tools

- Salesforce
- Lightning Platform
- Zoho
- Wordpress
- Instapage

Languagges

- Apex
- HTML
- Visualforce
- Javascript
- Bootstrap
- Deluge Script

EXPERIENCE

Salesforce Consultant —

Viswa Group, December 2019-Present

Involved as a Consultant which looks over the Salesforce Sales cloud and Service cloud. Manages the data of the different business units including data security and integrity and makes changes as per the business requirement. Maintaining the full database of the Customers along with the Sample counts of each Business and Product.

CRM Lead/Zoho Administrator

Viswa Group ,COE, Bangalore, India. Sep 2018 - Oct 2019

Complete involvement in analysis, design, implementation, automation and customizing the whole Organization Sales and Service Architecture, and HR tool using Salesforce and Zoho for different locations as a Lead.

Manages and collaborates with the team and assign them respectively. Review with their weekly report and worked on them based on changes.

Senior Engineer ———

Eon Education Pvt Ltd, Bangalore, India.Feb 2015 - Apr 2018

Worked on both the platforms, CRM and web-based applications development. Created complete layout of sales information where it stores the potential leads and converted leads using Salesforce tool. And developed web applications using Zoho.

KEY PROJECTS

1/:	Group-Digitizing	0-1 0	
VISWA	(3rolln-L)laiti7ino	SAIPS SVS	tem
VIOVA	aroup Digitizing	Carco Cyc	CIII

Implemented the complete Sales Architecture for different businesses using Salesforce Sales Cloud.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Understanding the requirement from Business Owners, Stakeholders and doing complete analysis on the requirement
- Discussing with the team, assigning systematically and working accordingly in the requirement and delivering timely.
- Maintaining a weekly report on team task report and the overall progress.
- Customized tabs for different business user groups and business centers.
- Customizing the complete Sales layout and used Lightning Process Builder to automate business process by providing a visual representation.
- Developed reports, dashboards, and processes to continuously monitor data quality and integrity
- Customized Websites and created email templates to enable Web-to-Lead and Emailto-Lead process.
- Used Triggers to automate some hard actions.
- Managing the user roles, Data integrity, Sharing rules for more data accuracy.
- Carried out Training session with Sales group to utilize Salesforce and respective programs.
- Worked on Sandbox environment, tested with all scenarios and deployed to the production site.
- Used App Exchange Tool to integrate with other applications to know the survey of the product.
- Worked on data migration from databases to SFDC using Data Loader.

Viswa Group-Service Cloud(Customer Service)

Implemented the complete Customer Service Department Architecture using service cloud console Salesforce.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Full analyze on the Architecture according to the business requirement.
- Made significant changes to Page Layouts and user Interface of the case management.
- Involved in Designing and Development of Workflow Rules, Validation Rules and Customizations within Salesforce.
- Complete 360 view console in Lightning Platform where Agent can go for quick response.
- Migration of Data from Zoho CRM to Salesforce.
- Used Workflows to govern data flow across various objects.
- Customized reports and dashboards according to the users hierarchy and access level
- Customized Websites and created email templates to enable Web-to-Case and Email-
- Used sandbox for testing and deployed to the production
- Carried out Training session with Sales group to utilize Salesforce and respective programs.
- Maintaining a weekly report on team task report and the overall progress.

Viswa Group-HR Cloud System

Created a cloud based HR portal for the Organization for managing all workforce and employee-related activities and concerns for different locations using Zoho People.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Collaborated with Hr department of different locations and done analysis.
- Customized the complete Tool of HR process and Finance process using Zoho People.
- Created different roles and hierarchy based on the position in the organizations.
- Created full automation flow on Leave Tracker, Over Time work hours, Performance module and Unpaid part.
- Managed on the complete Company Employee Data including all the documents.

Eon Education Sales Information

Creating a complete layout of sales information where it stores the potential leads and converted leads .This application gives full sales report.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Understanding the requirement from Sales Team and doing analysis on the requirement
- Developed Custom Objects, Custom Reports and dashboard on a regular basis for sales, performance and lead generation statics.
- Added custom fields and validations to new and existing objects
- Used Workflows to govern data flow across various objects.
- Defined lookup and master-detail relationships on the objects and created junction objects to establish connectivity among objects.
- Customized Websites and created email templates to enable Web-to-lead and Emailto-lead process.
- Creating a central database which stores all the customer information of all type business units.
- Managing the user roles, Data integrity, Sharing rules for more data accuracy.

Honeyfall ECommerce-Sales and Service Application

Developed full e-commerce Application that allows to track the the data related to all of the interactions. It's stored the complete information of sales of different products.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Complete CRM Implementation
- Build custom screen which caters the entire flow of sales.
- Workflow rules for some automation.

EDUCATION

- MCA from North Eastern Hill University(NEHU), Meghalaya in the year 2013
- BCA from Dibrugarh University, Assam in the year 2010.

CERTIFICATION

Salesforce Administrator (201), Trailhead

PERSONAL DETAILS

Nationality: *Indian* Date of birth: 29th July, 1988

Passport Number: S8380864 Visa: UAE Visa, Valid until: 20/11/2022